

Sao Paulo, Brazil

■ guilhermedanbail@gmail.com | 🖸 wbail | 🛅 guilherme-bail | 🥞 guilhermebail | Visa: Canada-B1

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary

Current working as Backend Developer at StoneCo Payments. 5+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and support. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience_

StoneCo Payments

Sao Paulo, Brazil

BACKEND DEVELOPER

Dec. 2020 - Current

- · One of the major fintechs in the country, transacting billions of operations between the end customers, companies and transaction processing.
- Develop API's in C# (.NET Core 3.1 and 5). The main responsibilities are: Think and design the software architecture always thinking in the best performance, scalability and testability possible.
- · Projects:
- Leads Api: The api was developed in .NET Core 5, EF Core 5, xUnity, Postgres. The main problem that the application solves is the delay between our customer (store) service aquisition and the capability to use it. Namely the delay occurred because was needed to send this new store to each card brand (Master Card, Visa, Amex, Dinners...) via email and wait their response via email again. With this api all this process is online and in real-time. The API received the store data and sends to each card brand automatically.

ExxonMobil Curitiba, Brazil

SYSTEM ANALYST

Aug. 2018 - Set. 2020

- As part of the development team (Scrum) I am responsible for providing solutions for Canada site. Developing in C# (.NET Core), Angular 2+ and PL/SQL as well as supporting more than 5000 users and 140 apps, between in house and vendor apps.
- Projects:
- Quality Prod Data: Backend developed in .NET Core, using Oracle database, REST API, frontend in Angular 8. Application used to upload many .csv's files with millions of records. The user simply send the folder path of the files.
- **Chatbot**: Developed a chatbot in C# for skype, using Luis API (Microsoft); to help the users solve problems, like: error messages, missing roles or request a software. If the bot could't solve the problem, opens a Work Order for the proper team that supports the application.
- Frontend consuming ticket api: Developed a frontend using Angular 2+ to help the users create Work Orders or Incidents for our team: selecting the software, attach a screenshot of the error. The main reason is to help users don't spend time going to help desk. (takes more time to help desk routes the ticket for the proper team)
- Server Upgrade: As part of OS upgrade from Windows 2008/2012 to Windows 2016, was needed rewrite the authentication method using C# of some applications, all these apps uses Oracle database.
- Having been responsible for the databases (Oracle and SQL Server), for the improvement and the task automation.
- Responsible for the most critical system that controls the fleet management (Distributed system in PL/SQL).
- Responsible for the contact between Company x Vendors for projects and upgrades. Also part of the SWAT team to solve as soon as possible critical production issues.

Easy Comm Tech. Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nov. 2017 - Jul. 2018

Jun. 2017 - Oct. 2017

- · Projects:
- Task/Project Contro: Implemented RESTful API using C# (.NET Core) applying SOLID principles as well as Repository pattern, consuming TFS API and exposing it to clients: Angular 2+ and desktop app
- Greenparing (Uber like for car dealers drivers): Finished a started project by another company, in Laravel (PHP). Implemented the integration between a FTP server and the application: The vendors uploads an .csv file everyday (car stock) and the system reads the file an populates the database. Implemented a new module for brand management. Correction of bugs in frontend using Bootstrap.
- Wheel Shop: Bugs fixes on backend in C# and frontend in Razor.
- Form Builder: Bug fixes on the frontend in AngularJS, the application is a drag and drop components to empower the users to build their own forms and lists.

Torzer Remote

• Proiect:

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Project:

• Parking Lot: Developed an application to control parking lots using Laravel (PHP) and Bootstrap. Generates and send receipts by email for the customers, the system is divided in two roles: Admin and Customer, with specific dashboards.

Ponta Grossa State University - Informatics Department

Ponta Grossa - Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov. 2016 - Jun. 2017

- · Projects:
- Remote Campus: Rewrite a legacy system in Laravel (PHP) and Boostrap for control the remote campus of the university, with three roles: Admin, Professor and Student. Each role with specific dashboard. Allow the Admin CRUD professors, students, classes, classes dates, generates certificates
- Final Paper: Created from scratch a system for control the Final Papers from the students in Laravel (PHP) and Bootstrap. With three roles: Admin, Professor and Student. Allowing the Admin CRUD the schedule for the professor/students. When the students uploads files versions of final papers, the professors receive an email for rate it. If the version isn't correct sends a notification for the student. Also the system sends a notification for professor and student if the schedule isn't being followed. Generates the documentation for the final paper presentation.

Education

UEPG(Ponta Grossa State University)

Ponta Grossa, Brazil

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Feb. 2013 - Nov. 2017

• Software Engineering, Development, Database, Network, Data Structures

Extracurricular Activity

Oracle Workshop 3 Ed

Curitiba - Brazil

StudentJul. 2019 - Jul. 2019

• An Oracle Workshop with the topics: Database management, user management, roles, tables, and the most common objects.

Junior Achievement - SOFTEJ Company

Ponta Grossa - Brazil

Co founder - Software Engineer

Feb. 2013 - Jun. 2017

- Founder member of a software company in the Informatics Department of the university
- · Helped to create the roles and responsibilities of the company.